离手
Clear!
充电
Charging!
离手
Clear!
不行了  可以宣布死亡了
Okay, I'm calling it.
死亡时间
Time of death...
8点32分
8:32.
你好啊  戴安娜
Hello, Diana.
我们开始吧
Shall we?
左室撕裂发生于一块新发坏死组织之中
LV tear is within a zone of fresh tissue necrosis,
显示近期出现过心肌梗死
implicating a recent myocardial infarction
这是致死原因
as the instigating event.
不幸的是  病历上说
Unfortunately, the medical records show
本扎医生从没有怀疑过是心脏病
that Dr. Penza never suspected heart disease,
而是误诊为哮喘  给予激素治疗
instead giving steroids for an erroneous diagnosis of asthma,
导致致命的心室撕裂
thereby causing the fatal tear.
我建议院方应对这些发现作出反应
I suggest these findings warrant further investigation
对本扎医生是否对病人负责进行调查
into Dr. Penza's standard of care for this patient,
这已经是我...
making this my...
今年第三次建议对本扎医生进行调查了
third such recommendation regarding Dr. Penza this year.
检查完脑后即完成本次尸检
Concluding autopsy with examination of the brain.
特莱柏医生
Dr. Treiber...
我很冷
I'm cold.
总监：
zlean
没错  这是哥的
Yes, it's mine.
没错  我知道我不会开手动档
And yes, I know that I can't drive stick.
对  我不在乎把车停在残疾人专用车位上
And no, I don't care that I parked in a handicapped spot.
"面对死神  我的生活就此改变"
"Staring death in the face has changed my life."
真是俗套啊
What a cliche.
人因此而过上更有意义的生活才俗呢
The cliche is to lead a more meaningful life.
而我发了毒誓
I've taken a holy vow
接下来要过没有意义的日子
to lead a less meaningful one.
我穷尽一生在关心别人
I've spent my life caring,
奉献  找寻更深刻的真谛
giving, and searching for the profound.
现在是时候自私一下  漠不关心
Now it's time for selfishness, indifference,
迎接肤浅的新生活了
and embracing the shallow.
你三天后拍片
Your scan's in three days.
告诉我这不是在你发现
Tell me this isn't just you killing time
癌症会要你命之前  你消磨时间的方式
until you find out if your cancer's gonna kill it for you.
我花了七万五  买了辆可笑又不实用的车
I just paid $75,000 for a ridiculously impractical car,
这可是肤浅至极了啊
the depth of shallowness.
明天  我要开着它去克利夫兰
And tomorrow, I'm driving it to Cleveland
去见我少年时代的梦中情人
to meet my boyhood crush.
岁月可没饶了大卫·卡西迪
The years have not been kind to David Cassidy.
是朱莉·克里斯蒂  演过《日瓦戈医生》
Julie Christie, Dr. Zhivago,
朱莉·克里斯蒂是1965年奥斯卡影后
《日瓦戈医生》于1965年上映
《洗发水》
Shampoo.
我有点早熟
I was precocious.
她好像开了一个
She's opening some kind of
慈善动物诊所还是什么的
charity animal clinic or something.
为了实现愚蠢的白日梦
I'm neglecting my patients
我要对我的病人不闻不问
to fulfill a silly fantasy.
这是教科书般的自私和漠不关心
Textbook selfishness and indifference.
或者你已经把你的病人都安排好了
Or you've made sure that your patients are well-covered,
这车是租的
car is a rental,
而你在等朱莉·克里斯蒂的签名照时
and while waiting to get Julie Christie's autograph,
顺便还会领养一只狗
you'll adopt a puppy.
我根本不介意你是否相信我
I don't even care whether you believe me or not.
漠不关心
Indifference.
他想把自己的脑袋切开
He tried to cut open his own skull.
头颅CT及毒物筛查无异常
Head CT and tox screen were clean.
有意思
Interesting.
虚无妄想综合征
Cotard delusion,
又名行尸综合征
also known as "Walking corpse syndrome."
扁桃体脱节
Disconnect in the amygdala convinces you
让你以为自己已经死了
that you're secretly dead.
问题解决
Case solved.
描述一下
Rendering it...
"有意思"的过去式是什么
what's the past-tense of "interesting?"
之前无精神疾病史
No prior history of mental illness,
在你说是由抗病毒药物引起之前
and before you say it was caused by antivirals,
我已经把它排除了
I've already ruled that out.
且虚无妄想综合征无法解释
Plus, Cotard's doesn't explain
他的手为何感觉异常
the paresthesia in his hand.
还有...
Also...
特莱柏不让其他医生接近他
Treiber won't let any other doctor near him.
他只相信你
He trusts your work.
病人是特莱柏吗
Treiber's the patient?
"有意思"的将来时是什么
What's the future tense of "interesting"?
威尔森怎么样了
How's Wilson doing?
威尔森的拍片安排在周末
Wilson's scan is at the end of the week.
若牛逼的化疗让肿瘤缩小到可以进行手术了
If his kick-ass chemo shrunk the tumor to an operable size,
他就能活下来
he'll live.
如果没有  他就死定了
If it didn't, he'll die.
这一定很难熬
That must be very hard.
我们能帮上什么忙吗
Is there anything we can do?
除了围个圈祈祷  还能干啥
Other than the prayer circle, what is there?
患者谷草转氨酶很高
Patient's AST is high.
肝衰竭可致精神异常
Psychosis could be brought on by liver failure.
也许是丙肝
Maybe Hep C?
胆红素血清蛋白水平无异常
Bilirubin and serum protein levels were normal.
解释不了他刺痛的手
Doesn't explain the tingly hand
和奇斯为什么恨他
or why Chase hates him.
我不恨他  是他恨我
I don't hate him. He hates me.
他痛恨所有医生  而且恨是双向的
He hates all doctors, and it's mutual.
他只恨那些搞砸的医生
He only hates the ones that screw up,
还有你
and you.
那些医生恨特莱柏
And they only hate Treiber
是因为他发现了他们的失误
because he finds their mistakes.
在死人身上找错误简单多了
Mistakes are a wee bit easier to find on a dead patient.
这么大的区别他看不出来
A distinction he fails to recognize.
他就是找茬
He's a rat.
是谁通过让医生更负责更专注
Who makes the hospital a safer place
从而保障医院的治愈率的
by keeping doctors accountable and focused.
会不会他从尸体上传染上什么病
What if he got something from a cadaver?
他经手的可不少了
He handles a lot of 'em.
你的意思是要逐一作鉴别诊断吗
You suggesting we DDX them all?
不用  就最后一个
No, just his last one.
她膝盖不好
She had bad knees.
她用二甲基亚砜治疗关节痛
She used dimethyl sulfoxide for joint pain.
除颤仪产生的电流
Current from the defibrillator
可使其产生二甲硫
could've converted it to dimethyl sulfate.
当特莱柏切开她时
When Treiber cut into her,
毒素通过她的血液散发出来
her blood released toxic fumes.
那样的话所有在地下室的人都会生病
Everyone in the basement would be sick.
气体也不会扩散得那么快
Gas would've dissipated quickly.
他肺部正常  血栓更合理一点
His lungs are fine. Blood clots make more sense.
血栓在手部可以解释他的感觉异常
One in his hand explains the paresthesia,
血栓在颈动脉可以解释他的精神错乱
one in his carotid explains the psychotic episode.
你们俩去找暴露出来的毒素
You two look for toxic exposure.
亚当斯  你去帮奇斯
Adams, you can help Chase ultrasound
给他的死敌做B超  找那邪恶的血栓
his evil nemesis for evil clots.
我知道豪斯不喜欢见病人
I know House doesn't like seeing his patients,
但同事找他看病  就不能特别对待吗
but doesn't a fellow doctor rate an exception?
精神症状似乎是间断发作
Psychosis appears to be intermittent.
我多几句嘴就是想确认一下
Just snapped out of it long enough to ask
这检查是不是豪斯让做的
if House actually ordered this test.
别担心
Don't worry.
我们只是在执行他的命令罢了
We're simply carrying out his direct orders.
对  我忘了你就是被雇来干这活的
Right. Forgot it's what you were hired to do.
这无所谓  他的误诊率是0.17
Which is fine, his diagnostic error metric
比医院平均水平0.32低多了
is .17 compared to the hospital average of .32.
你真的认为你能用数据
You actually think you can quantify
来评估每位医生吗
the value of every doctor?
应该统计统计吧
Someone should.
而我正是唯一能看清一切的人
And since I'm the only one who sees everything.
可不是  雇你来就是要你
Right, you were hired to diagnose people
诊断死人的
after they're already dead.
未见血管管腔狭窄及血栓
No sign of stenosis or clots.
每个医生  诊断  治疗方式  结果
Every doctor, every diagnosis, every treatment, every result.
真是惊人
It's pretty impressive.
真是个阴谋论者
It's pretty Orwellian.
Orwellian  源自英国作家乔治·奥威尔
比喻极权式的统治方式
全是暗码
All written in his secret code.
他必须保密
He has to keep it confidential.
就像万塞会议
Just like the Wannsee Conference.
用"老大哥"打比喻还不够吗
The "Big Brother" metaphor wasn't pointed enough for you?
还要加上希特勒
You had to throw in Hitler?
几年前
A couple years ago,
他发现了儿童死亡之间的联系
he noticed a link in child deaths,
彻底改变了医院制度
and it's completely changed hospital policies all over--
我知道  特莱柏是书呆子之王
I get it. Treiber is nerd king.
我们杀的越多  他救的就越多
The more people we kill, the more lives he saves.
二甲硫检查结果呈阴性
Test is negative for dimethyl sulfate.
她的血液中无毒
Her blood is not toxic.
那我们应该找找别的毒物源
Then we should look for toxic exposure from something else.
你真的认为医院会白痴到
You really think the hospital is idiotic enough
连有毒器具也提供吗
to issue toxic supplies?
你没看到他的工具吗
Have you seen his tools?
特莱柏不总是用医院标准工具
Treiber doesn't always use hospital-issue.
那他才是白痴吗
Then he's the idiot?
不是  我可不想
No, but I don't want to
向豪斯做解释
explain that assumption to House.
-有发现了  -有发现了
- Found something. - Found something.
我们应该来次自驾游
Thought we'd make it a road trip.
80年代的音乐  垃圾食品  啤酒
'80s music, junk food, beer.
我和牙医有约
I have a dental appointment,
现在就打电话预约
that I'm going to make now.
我会让你开车哦
Ah. I'll let you drive.
只为一连三天听你哭诉
Not worth listening to you whine
你的心情和恐惧  不值得
about your feelings and fears for three days.
不可能的事  我已经发誓了
It's not gonna happen. I've taken a vow.
人是不会变的  你是人  因此我不去
People don't change. You are a person, ergo, pass.
这就是为何我带上了这个
Yes, that's why I brought this.
20毫升丙泊酚[麻醉剂]
20CCs of propofol.
你可以自愿和我走
You can accompany me willingly,
不然我就在你不经意的时候
or I will, when you least expect it,
往你血管里注射一小瓶这玩意
inject the contents of this vial into your bloodstream.
摔倒可引起脑震荡
The fall might result in a concussion,
或者骨折
or fractures,
也许你会走运
or you might get lucky
醒来后发现人在阿伦敦[滨州]
and simply wake up somewhere near Allentown
只是有点头疼
with a nasty headache.
选择权还是你的  而且你可别忘了
The choice is yours, and in case you've forgotten,
我怎样都无所谓
I am indifferent.
明早8点出发
We leave tomorrow morning at 8:00 a.m.
没血栓
No clots.
没毒素
No gas.
可我们发现了这个
But we found enough of this
多得足以引起尸变了
to reanimate the entire morgue.
他以咖啡因为食
He's jacked on caffeine.
兴奋剂所致精神病
Stimulant psychosis.
我又一次完成了对他的诊断
How many times do I have to solve this case?
我们要做的就是
So all we have to do is
水化治疗并观察24小时
hydrate and observe him for 24 hours.
为何不告诉他这是你的主意
Why don't you tell him it was your idea?
也许他会对你有所改观
He might warm up to you.
如果邮箱里收到一只耳朵
If you get an ear in the mail,
十有八九是我的
it's probably mine.
我的腹部
My abdomen!
我的腹部疼
It's my abdomen!
撤药反应而已
It's just the effects of withdrawal.
这种疼痛属正常
The pain is normal.
不  不
No! No!
这不对劲
This isn't right!
腹部胀痛
Abdominal pain and distention
这么说应该不是兴奋剂所致精神病
Means we were wrong about stimulant psychosis.
可能是同时患多种病
It could be coexistent problems.
也许只是肠梗阻
He might just have an obstruction.
你知道豪斯是怎么看巧合这种事的
You know what House says about coincidences.
我为他做检查时  未发现任何包块
I didn't feel any masses when I examined him,
也没有肠音
and no bowel sounds.
豪斯去哪儿了
Where's House?
他还没来呢  威尔森也是
He hasn't come in yet, and neither has Wilson.
我已经给他打了三次电话了
I've--I've already tried him three times.
又来了
Here we go again.
糖尿病可能引起手部
Diabetes could cause nerve damage in his hand,
和内脏神经受损  而且
and guts, and--
但是他的血糖水平正常
Except his glucose levels are normal.
而且如果他有糖尿病  肯定早就说了
And he probably would've mentioned he was a diabetic.
会不会是溃疡性结肠炎
What about ulcerative colitis?
先前的发作引起血栓形成
Earlier attacks caused thrombosis--
我们早已试着找过血块
We already looked for clots,
而且他的大便潜血阴性
and there was no blood in his stool.
再试试打给他
Try him again.
还有威尔森的
And Wilson's.
不管他们在哪儿  似乎不愿意被打扰
Wherever they are, they don't want to be disturbed.
我们走78号公路
We take 78.
可以沿路把各种美食吃个遍
We can do those "sweet treats and salty eats snack food trail."
我的旅游  我做主
My trip, my itinerary.
我们今天得开300英里
We have to cover 300 miles today
这样才有时间在明天4点前
to be there with plenty of time
赶到朱莉那
to catch Julie by 4:00 tomorrow.
我不是说过要让你开车吗
And that thing I said about letting you drive,
我撒谎了
I lied.
怎么了
What?
我  我真是佩服
I'm--I'm impressed.
不是说你的车技
Not by that.
是说你这么努力  维持毫不在乎的假象
But by your real effort to maintain the facade.
几乎一小时了
It's been almost an hour,
还没提到那个不容忽视的话题呢
and there's been no mention of the elephant in the car.
我拒绝探讨这个话题
Well, I declined the elephant option.
三天之后  你就会得知
In three days, you're gonna find out
自己是死是活
if you live or die.
你不想谈这个话题
You don't want to talk about it.
我不想  但显然你想谈
No, but obviously you do.
那我们是要谈谈
So, we're gonna talk about it,
但也是因为是我想谈
but because I want to.
我不想讨论这件事
I am neither talking about it,
也不想讨论为何不谈这件事
nor talking about not talking about it.
你这种人叫你不谈也不行
You are hard-wired to talk about it.
这是你的应付方式  这就是你
It's how you cope, it's who you are.
是吗  不过
Yeah, well,
从现在开始  我就不是我了
from now on, I'm not me.
我是...我是...
I'm...I'm...
凯尔·卡洛威
Kyle Calloway.
你的色情明星名是鲁斯蒂·帕卡得
I thought your porn name was Rusty Packard.
凯尔无忧无虑  有大侠风范
Kyle is roguish, carefree,
和詹姆斯·威尔森全然不是一路人
and shares no qualities with James Wilson.
凯尔会开手动档吗
Can Kyle drive stick?
豪斯不在的话  特莱柏不会配合治疗
Treiber won't let us do anything without House.
豪斯自动放弃这个病例了
House just took himself off the case.
你说检查的时候未见肠音
You said no bowel sounds when you examined him.
是根本没有呢  还是声音较轻
"No" like diminished, or none at all?
-是根本没有  -你觉得是肠套叠
- None. - You think it's an intussusception?
如果是的话  很可能是癌症
If it is, it could mean cancer's behind everything.
给他拍个腹部平片
Let's get a plain film of his abdomen.
只要不是豪斯的意见
Treiber will refuse any procedure
特莱柏都不会同意的
that wasn't ordered by House.
别告诉他不就得了
Only if he knows it wasn't.
这家伙最喜欢找医生的麻烦
You want to lie to a guy whose favorite pastime
你还要对他撒谎
is getting doctors fired.
我们都是经过严格医疗训练的医生
We're adults with advanced medical training,
不是些没人管的毛孩子
not children left alone with scissors.
就做个X光片
It's one X-ray.
如果带着手机
If we had a phone,
我们就能找个像样点的地方
we could've found somewhere a little less charming.
如果带着手机  你肯定会打电话
If we had a phone, you'd be making calls,
下毛片  玩愤怒的小鸟
downloading porn, and playing angry birds.
这次旅行我说了算  我就喜欢这里
This trip is about me, and I like this place.
这事儿和你不希望我带手机没关系
This is not about you not wanting me to have a phone.
是你太软弱
You're weak.
你知道自己会退缩
You knew that you'd backslide
给你哭哭啼啼的前妻和父母打电话
and spend your time talking to teary ex-wives and your parents,
安慰他们别太担心你的病
trying to make them feel better about you being sick.
培根汉堡配薯条看上去很难吃
Bacon burger with fries looks awful.
我尝尝吧
I'll have that.
我要个大汉堡
I'll have the big one.
你肯定吗  那个要79美元
You sure? It's $79.
要是在一小时内吃完
Unless I finish it in an hour,
就是免费的
in which case, it's free.
那可是两公斤的牛排啊
It's an 80-ounce steak.
我饿着呢  再来杯冰茶
I'm hungry. And an iced tea, please.
上大汉堡
Big one's up!
这地方可不能刷信用卡
This place doesn't take credit cards.
我这顿会免单的
My meal is going to be free,
而且  我的名字还会刻在痛苦之墙上
and I'm going to be inducted into the wall of pain.
痛苦之墙
大汉堡之家
你好啊  凯尔
Hello, Kyle.
腹部平片正常
Belly film was normal.
未见肠套叠及肠梗阻征象
No sign of an intussusception or any other obstruction.
豪斯说有的
House says it's there.
豪斯也会犯错
Sometimes House is wrong.
彻底检查下
Run my bowel.
那可是个大手术
That's serious surgery.
要全身麻醉  且恢复时间长
General anesthesia, long recovery...
如你需要更多证据可做个钡灌肠
We can do a contrast enema if you need more proof.
我见过无数死者  都是正常的检查结果
I have drawers filled with people who had clean scans.
我很清楚很容易出现漏查
I know how easy it is to miss something
除非是直接用手和眼睛
unless you use your own hands and eyes,
给我做彻底检查
run my bowel.
你的感受我们会告诉豪斯
We'll let House know how you feel.
我的感受就是肚子疼死了
How I feel is twisted in white-hot agony.
他的诊断是检查肠套叠
His orders were to look for an intussusception.
在彻底检查之前  我拒绝其他检查
Until you actually do that, I refuse any other tests.
好吧
Fine.
不行  不行  我们得和...
Uh, no. Not fine. We need to talk...
我要你给我做手术
And I want you to do the surgery.
数据上来看  你是医院里最好的外科医生
Statistically, you're the best surgeon in the hospital.
凯尔  凯尔  凯尔
Kyle! Kyle! Kyle!
加油  你能赢
Come on, you got this!
能赢的
You got this!
加油
Come on!
还有二十五秒
25 seconds.
胜券在握
You've got this.
加油  最后冲刺了  凯尔  最后冲刺
Come on, home stretch, Kyle, home stretch!
还有十五秒
15 seconds!
别嚼了  直接吞
Now, don't chew, just swallow.
硬吞
Muscle it down!
六  五...
Six, five...
四
Four...
看在上帝份上  吞啊
For the love of god, swallow!
三  二  一
Three, two, one...
时间到
Time!
成了  成了
Yes! Yes!
你个混蛋干得太好了
Oh, you magnificent bastard!
笑一个
Smile!
还算吃完了  对吧
That still counts, though, right?
没情绪吧
No hard feelings, right?
等你醒了就知道了
You'll find out when you wake up.
你真觉得我是个优秀的医生
If you really think I'm a good doctor,
为什么把我当白痴一样
why do you treat me like an idiot?
不是说你没天赋
It's not because you lack talent.
只是因为你浪费了才华
It's 'cause you've wasted it.
你知道吗  我和你同一年申请
Did you know I applied to be a fellow with House
在豪斯手下工作
the same year as you?
不知道
No.
我放弃了其他项目  搬了家
Quit my other program, relocated,
和女友分了手
broke up with my girlfriend.
后来  你父亲通了关系
Then your father made a call,
那位子就被你抢去了
and suddenly you had the spot.
那是将近十年前的事情吧
That was almost ten years ago.
你知道  若是我跟了豪斯
Do you know what I could've done
三年之内  会有怎样的成就吗
after even three years with House?
很可能去疾病控制中心
Gone to the CDC,
或世界卫生组织
W.H.O.
在一个从未听说过
Started a diagnostics department
诊断部的医院  建立自己的部门
someplace they'd never even heard of such a thing.
你拥有了一切
You've been given everything.
相貌  才华
Looks, talent,
连同我的未来
my future.
九年过去了  看看你现在的样子
Nine years later, look what you've done with it.
吃饭吃到吐的感觉还不错吧
Must be nice to be puking for the old-fashioned reasons.
很高兴我挑战过了
I'm glad I did it.
你看到那些人为我加油的样子吗
You see those people out there cheering for me?
我是个英雄
I was a hero.
就那么一小会儿
For one fleeting moment,
就因为那么愚蠢的事
for an incredibly stupid reason,
在一群无缘再见的傻瓜心中  我是英雄
for a bunch of morons I'll never see again.
老天  这感觉真好
God, it felt good.
失陪了
And now, if you'll excuse me.
我吐完想再吃点甜点
I think I've made room for dessert.
你打算跟着豪斯干多久
How long do you think you'll work for House?
只要他允许  一直干下去
As long as he lets me.
豪斯在监狱的时候
When House was in prison,
你在仁爱医院干整容
You worked at Mercy in plastics, right?
你知道那会我干什么吗
Know what I did?
冲浪  整整九个月
Surfed. For nine months.
是啊  要不是我有两个孩子要养
Yes, and if I didn't have two daughters
有赡养费要交
and alimony,
我可能也去冲浪了
I might have done the same.
学徒阶段之后  你就应该自立门户
A fellowship's supposed to train you to stand on your own.
福曼当了院长
Foreman's dean of the hospital,
卡梅隆在芝加哥医院当了急症部主任
Cameron's head of emergency medicine in Chicago.
卡特那和安波儿死了
And Kutner and Amber are dead.
十三说不定在什么小岛上享受鱼水之欢
And thirteen is having sweet, sapphic sex on some island.
看这个
Look at this.
小肠这里
The small intestine.
是肠套叠吗
Is it an intussusception?
不是
No.
看来被特莱柏说中了
Guess Treiber was right.
他就没查过语音信箱
He hasn't checked his voicemail.
也没看邮箱
Or his email.
已经快24小时了
It's been almost 24 hours.
是不是该通知福曼或叫警察啊
Shouldn't we call Foreman or the police?
我想他算是逃犯了吧
I think this makes him a fugitive.
我们不用通知任何人
We don't have to tell anyone.
特莱柏的症状最先出现在额叶
Treiber's symptoms started in his frontal lobe,
然后波及神经系统
and moved through his nervous system,
手  小肠  肌肉
hands, bowels, muscles.
-间歇性卟啉症  -他正在发作期
- Intermittent porphyria. - He's in the middle of an attack.
应用血红素治疗  等得越久
The longer we wait to treat with hemin,
造成的伤害越大
the more damage it causes.
我们应告诉他豪斯不知所踪  瞒得越久
The longer we wait to tell him House isn't running the case,
才会带来更大的伤害
the more damage that causes.
这是欺瞒病人
It's fraud.
若我们诊断错误  这才会是问题
It's only an issue if we're wrong.
这回可不是照X光片这么简单
It's more than one X-ray.
也不仅仅是做探查性手术了
more than exploratory surgery, even.
万一你错了  用此药会造成生理损伤
This is a drug that will damage him if you're wrong.
道理是一样的
Same principle.
我想来次3P
I want a threesome.
要不咱俩先单练吧
Shouldn't we try a twosome first?
是和两个女的
Two women.
我知道大家可能夸大其词
I know they're probably overrated,
而我完事后可能会极其失望
and I'll probably be gravely disappointed.
但我还是想试一次
But I want one anyway.
不  你不想
No, you don't.
凯尔想来一炮
Well, Kyle wants one.
你变身为凯尔才一天
Kyle's only one day old.
哪知道自己要什么
He doesn't know what he wants.
我不关心结果
I don't want to think about consequences.
我不在乎...
I don't want to think about--
我什么都不在乎
I don't want to think about anything.
只想经历一下
I just want to do.
行
OKay.
那你必须完全按我说的做
I need you to do exactly what I tell you.
没问题
Yeah, yeah.
卟啉症吗
Porphyria?
我知道麻醉让你难以集中精力
I know the anesthesia makes it hard to focus,
但我们需要立即开始给你用血红素
but we need to start you on hemin right away.
豪斯对这个诊断很有把握
House believes very strongly.
这是正确的方案
This is the right call.
好吧
Okay.
这玩意不服帖
This thing is peeling.
没办法  这就是胆小的代价
Well, that is the cost of cowardice.
你应该真剃光头的
Should've gone for the real thing.
我感觉我在欺骗别人
I feel like I'm cheating.
第一  若你没得癌症这才是欺骗
A, it is only cheating if you don't have cancer,
第二  现在是周三下午
and B, it's Wednesday afternoon.
没什么人
Pickings are slim.
而更重要的是  没人喝醉
And more importantly, sober.
患癌症这招用来钓妹子屡试不爽
The cancer cut is the surest way to the pity pooty party.
搞定一个  还差一个
One down, one to go.
什么  等等
What? Wait, wait, wait.
她同意了吗
She said yes?
我可是要3P哦
To a threesome?
她极富同情心
She's empathetic.
她是妓女吧
She's a hooker.
-还给我打折了呢  -不要
- Gave me a cancer rate. - No.
我这辈子都没花钱找人上床过
I have never paid for sex in my life.
不用你掏钱
You still haven't.
我请客
It's my treat.
你要么接受  要么自己在接下来的一小时里
It's either that, or you find two very open-minded women
找到两个开放的女人同时爱上你
to fall in love with you in the next hour.
那个酒保看着不错
Bartender seems nice.
挺女人的
Seems female.
想要吃点什么吗
Want something to eat?
我朋友身患癌症  命不久矣
My friend is dying of cancer.
太可怜了
Oh, you poor thing.
我母亲两年前患癌症去世了
It took my mother two years ago.
但不要放弃希望
But you can't give up hope.
他基本上是放弃了
He's pretty much resigned.
只想死前轰轰烈烈干一场
Just wants to go out with a bang.
话说回来  你什么时候下班
And another pun, what time do you get off?
出现胸腔积液  不是卟啉症
Pleural effusions. It's not porphyria.
我们需要放胸腔引流管
We're gonna need to put in a chest tube.
我要见豪斯
I wanna talk to House.
我们会原原本本地告诉他
We'll tell him exactly what's happening.
我要亲自说
I wanna talk to him!
让豪斯来
I want House.
豪斯在哪里
Where is House?
他在哪呢
Where is he?
豪斯去哪了
Where's House?
我们不知道
We don't know.
你不用睡在外面的
You didn't have to sleep out here.
四个人太挤了
Four's a crowd.
其实她们很早就离开了
Apparently they left a long time ago.
感觉如何
So, how was it?
那个酒保和性爱专家哪个好
Was the amateur as good as the pro?
我说不清
It was confusing.
勉强吧
Perfunctory.
-有点伤感  -当我没问
- A bit sad. - Never mind.
但这正是我需要的
And exactly what I needed.
谢谢
Thank you.
你愿意请我吃早饭吗
You feel like buying me breakfast?
其中一人顺走了我的钱包
One of them stole my wallet.
他不起诉  算你走运
You're lucky he's not pressing charges.
卟啉症是很合理的诊断
Porphyria was a legitimate call.
直到出现胸腔积液
Until the pleural effusions.
我们不过是做了豪斯在这会做的事
We've done everything House would've done if he'd been here.
你向病人撒谎了
You lied to a patient.
特莱柏的状况急剧恶化
Treiber's condition is declining rapidly.
他同意让我接手治疗
He's agreed to let me take over the case.
奇斯医生不能再与病人有任何接触
Dr. Chase will have no further contact with the patient.
行
Fine.
我没说把你调离此案
I didn't say you were off the case.
坐下
Sit down.
做了心脏核磁共振
Ordered a cardiac MRI.
左心室增大
Enlargement of the left ventricle
表明是侵润性病变
suggests an infiltrative disease.
是结节病
It's sarcoidosis.
用皮质激素开始治疗
We'll start him on corticosteroids
并做心脏活检来确诊
and do a cardiac biopsy to confirm.
我不同意  卟啉症这一诊断我弄错了
I disagree. I was wrong about the porphyria,
但关于神经系统的判断是正确的
but I wasn't wrong about the nervous system.
是朊病毒病
It's a prion disease.
所以他的症状才会发展得这么快
That's why his symptoms have progressed so rapidly.
很可能他暴露于病毒源而不自知
It's possible he was exposed and didn't know it.
尸检后  脑部要存放很久才做检查
Brains are often stored and not tested until weeks after autopsy.
特莱柏很优秀  不会这么不谨慎
Treiber's too good to not take the right precautions.
也许问题就在于他也这么想
Maybe the problem is he thinks the same thing.
他的工作就是建立在
His job's built on the premise
医生会犯错这一假设之上  他也是医生
that doctors make mistakes; that includes him.
我们应该做脑活检
We should do a brain biopsy.
在这种情况下
In his condition?
那我们只能在尸检时进行脑活检了
Then we biopsy the brains in the morgue.
找出感染他的东西
Find the one that exposed him.
这简直就是大海捞针
It's a needle in a haystack.
我们有四个人
There's four of us.
我们至少可以
Come on, we can at least
在你们做心脏活检的时候
start him on amphotericin to halt the progress
给他用两性霉素来控制病情
while you do your heart biopsy.
不  不行  两性霉素加上活检用的造影剂
No, we can't. Amphotericin plus the contrast dye
他的肾脏受不了
for the biopsy would overwhelm his kidneys.
我们只能二选其一
We have to choose one or the other.
进行心脏活检
Biopsy his heart.
钱包要放到迷你吧台的冰箱里
Wallets go in the minibar freezer.
如果没有迷你吧台那就要放到马桶水箱里
If there's no minibar, the toilet tank.
我只剩下二十块整了
I've got exactly $20 left.
不好意思  我对招妓规则不熟悉
I'm sorry, I wasn't familiar with hooker protocol.
我们可以用你的信用卡
We can use your credit cards.
不  不行
No, we won't.
我还在缓刑期
I'm still on probation.
没有经过允许出州
Leaving the state without permission
就真的会让我的缓刑期无限延长了
will really P.O. my P.O.
没所谓
Doesn't matter.
我们都买不起回家的汽油
We can't even afford gas to get home.
已经比计划晚了三小时了
We're three hours behind schedule.
我们有足够的油去到朱莉那
We have enough gas to get to Julie.
其他的一切我都不在乎
I don't care about anything else.
又怎么了
What this time?
我就想知道你这种状态会持续多久
Just wondering how long this can last.
你还在寄希望于我幡然悔悟
You're still hoping that I'm gonna wake up
然后承认凯尔·卡洛威只是
and admit that Kyle Calloway is just
我为了找乐子编出来的破理由  对吗
some lame excuse to have some naughty thrills aren't you?
事实上我希望你不是
I'm actually hoping you won't.
我喜欢凯尔
I like Kyle.
不是吧
Oh, come on.
走啊  走啊
Move! Move!
豪斯
House.
你还好吗
You okay?
我腿还是很疼
My leg still hurts.
来吧
Come on.
我们有二十块得走十一英里
We got 20 bucks to go 11 miles.
你为什么不回寻呼
Why aren't you answering your pages?
忙着呢
Busy.
活检结果显示心肌纤维化
The biopsy showed fibrosis in his cardiac muscle.
所以不是阮病毒病
So it's not a prion disease.
就是说福曼也错了
It means Foreman was wrong too.
他要所有人去他办公室做鉴别诊断
He wants everyone to meet in his office to DDX.
然后他来告诉我们病因是感染吗
So he can tell us all it's an infection?
有意思  或者你应该考虑
Interesting. Or maybe you should consider
不要再这么幼稚下去
not being such a baby.
第一感觉是被尸体感染
First instinct was an exposure from a corpse.
特莱柏所有的时间都在这
Treiber spends all his time here.
如果不是有毒气体
If it's not toxic gas,
也不是阮病毒...
not prions...
那就是别的什么东西
Then it has to be something else.
他也不是完美的
He's not perfect.
你究竟是想治好他还是想让他丢脸
Are you trying to cure him or discredit him?
特莱柏只知道我不是豪斯
Treiber can only see me as not House.
福曼也是这样
Foreman too.
他们没错
And they're not wrong.
这么说你不到楼上来吗
So you're not coming upstairs.
不
No.
等这个病例结束后
And when this case is over,
我就辞职
I'm quitting.
他不会辞职
He's not quitting.
他已经开始联系其他医院了
He already called other hospitals.
特莱柏确实惹到他了
Treiber did get under his skin.
他会好的
He'll get over it.
纤维化应该是机体对感染的反应
Fibrosis has to be a response to an infection.
奇斯说过你会这么说的
Chase said you'd say that.
我们再用活检样本检测一下病毒
We'll test the biopsy samples for viruses
然后给他用抗病毒药
and start him on antivirals.
你都不打算跟奇斯谈谈吗
You're not even gonna talk to Chase?
他被刺中心脏都没离开
He didn't leave after he got stabbed in the heart.
我认为没问题
I think we're okay.
要么你是对的
Either you're right,
你朋友只很沮丧而已
and your friend is just really upset,
或者你错了  他是出于理智作出这个决定
or you're wrong, and he's come at this calmly and rationally,
而你就会失去一名好医生
and you're about to lose a good doctor.
无论怎样...
Either way...
这里是俄亥俄州的奥布里特
This is Oubliette, Ohio.
从1968年开始就没公共汽车了
Buses don't run here after 1968.
伊娜说这里每十五分钟就会有一辆公共汽车
Ina said there's a bus every 15 minutes.
伊娜她老年痴呆着呢
Ina is living in Alzheimersville.
我们在这已经至少半个小时了
Been here at least half an hour.
你要去哪伊娜
Where are you going, Ina?
那不勒斯 佛罗里达
Naples, Florida.
我和本在那有间漂亮的三室公寓
Ben and I have a beautiful three-bedroom condo.
都在同一层
All on the one floor.
你在等去那不勒斯的公共汽车吗
You're waiting for a bus to Naples?
每十五分钟有一趟
Comes every 15 minutes.
本肯定在想他的晚饭了
Ben'll be wondering where his dinner is.
出租车
Cab.
Whoa, cab!
二十块  十一公里  来吧
20 bucks, 11 miles. Come on.
来吧  走吧
Come on, let's go.
朱莉至少还会在诊所里
Julie's gonna be at the clinic
待45分钟  我们能赶上
for another 45 minutes. We can make this.
她以为她在佛罗里达
She thinks she's in Florida.
好吧  我们带她一起
Okay, bring her with.
我在等公共汽车
I'm waiting for the bus.
车不会来的  伊娜  但这辆出租会带我们去那不勒斯
Bus isn't coming, Ina. But this cab is going to Naples.
本要饿坏了
Ben'll be getting awfully hungry.
豪斯
House.
我们可以让出租司机叫警察来
We'll tell the cabbie to call the cops.
他们会来接她并照顾好她的
They'll come pick her up, take care of her.
那我就陪着她等警察过来
Then I'll stay with her until they do.
再见了  凯尔
Good-bye, Kyle.
每15分钟就有一趟公车
Bus comes every 15 minutes.
闭嘴吧
Oh, shut up.
发现什么了吗
Find anything?
还没
Not yet.
正在检测耐甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌
Running tests for MRSA.
你让所有人都担心你要辞职的事
You've got everybody worried about your quitting.
你是作为我朋友还是老板在这说话的
You here as my boss or my friend?
如果我是作为老板在这  那你早被停职了
If I was here as your boss, you'd be suspended by now.
我在这里学到了很多
I've learned a lot here.
足够组建自己的团队了
Enough to run my own team.
是时候向前看了
It's time I moved on.
很不幸这是我去年的感觉了
Unfortunately, that's how I felt last year.
还有前年
And the year before that.
或许你没离开是有原因的
Maybe there's a reason you haven't left.
你需要秩序
You need structure.
需要支撑
And support.
需要有人来做决断
Somebody else calling the shots.
你不是以老板或者朋友的身份来找我
You didn't come down here as my boss or my friend.
你扮的是豪斯
You came down as House.
你想用激将法激我做出决定
You're trying to insult me into making a decision.
你我都见过这招奏效
We've both seen it work.
你要么迎接挑战  并且辞职
Either you rise to the challenge and quit,
要么就留下
or you stay.
做好团队配合
As a team member.
特莱柏医生
Dr. Treiber!
Dr. Treiber.
换输液袋的时候他忽然没反应了
He stopped responding when I was changing his I.V. Bag.
彼得  睁开眼睛
Peter, open your eyes.
昏迷
Coma.
特莱柏昏迷了
Treiber's comatose.
全体成员集合意见
All brains on deck.
哪里开始  我们认为你可能是对的
Where should we start? We think you might be right.
我错了
I'm not.
你不可能都检过了
You couldn't have gone through all of these.
不需要
Don't have to.
特莱柏的报告无可挑剔
Treiber's reports are thorough to a fault.
方法精益求精
His methods are fastidious.
答案不在这里
The answer isn't down here.
特莱柏没有疏漏  我们有
Treiber didn't miss anything. We did.
怎讲
So what?
精神异常  腹痛  胸腔积液
Psychosis, abdominal pain, pleural effusions,
心脏扩大  昏迷
enlarged heart, coma.
自身免疫疾病  可能是肺出血肾炎综合征
Autoimmune, maybe Goodpasture's.
肾脏无异常  血管炎
Kidneys are fine. Vasculitis?
-没有发热  -淋巴瘤
- No fever. - Lymphoma?
心脏活检中早该发现
Would've seen it on the heart biopsy.
洗手液
Soap.
是洗手液
It's the soap.
是我搞糟了
I blew it.
天哪  终于开始了
Oh, God, here it comes.
一如既往
As always.
我不过想抛开一切取乐
All I wanted was some meaningless fun,
却连三天都坚持不了
and I couldn't even last three days.
熟睡中
Sound asleep.
这是梦话
I'm sleep talking.
实现毕生梦想的机会就摆在我的面前
I had the chance to fulfill a lifelong dream.
我发誓  你不闭嘴
I swear, I will jump out of this moving bus
我就跳车
if you don't shut up.
我却陪一个可悲的老妇坐了一个半钟头
But instead, I sat with a sad, old woman for 1 1/2 hours
分别才三秒钟她就忘了我的存在
who forgot I existed three seconds after she left.
最傻的是
And the stupidest thing.
我根本没喜欢过朱莉·克里斯蒂
I never even had a crush on Julie Christie.
高三时我疯狂地爱上梅拉妮·罗宾斯
In 12th grade I was madly in love with Melanie Robbins,
她长得像极了《日瓦戈医生》
who happened to look exactly like Julie Christie
里的朱莉·克里斯蒂
in Dr. Zhivago.
她也喜欢我
And she really liked me.
每天中午我们都在查理顿老师的教室里玩牌
Played spades every lunch period in Mr. Charlton's classroom.
当然了  她有别的追求者
But of course, there was this other guy.
厉害家伙  人缘好  有车
A great guy. Very popular. He had a car.
有乐队
He had a band,
留小胡子
a mustache...
凯尔·卡洛威
Kyle Calloway.
我当时想...
I assumed that...
我希望能和她一起去毕业舞会
I hoped that we would go to the senior prom together,
可是她求我帮忙
but she asked me for a favor.
她问
She asked...
我介不介意她陪他去
If I minded if she went with him.
她问我  介不介意
She asked me if I minded.
我说不介意
And I said I didn't.
就是这样
And that was it.
而我刚刚又做了同样的事
And I just did it again.
我放弃了
I let it go,
一如我放弃所有
like I let everything go.
所以我到了这里  坐在这辆巴士上
And here I am, sitting on this bus,
拿着用手表换来的车票
with tickets I bought with my watch,
赶回家去  就为了
heading back home, so a...
为了让一次CT扫描决定我的命运
a CT scan can decide my f-fate.
我不想回去  豪斯
I don't wanna go back, House.
我只想
I just...
我只想继续做凯尔
I just wanna keep being Kyle.
凯尔会丢下巴士站那可悲的老妇不管
Kyle would've ditched that sad, old woman from the bus stop.
很可能也会丢下我
Probably would've ditched me too.
没了凯尔我也一样活
I can live without Kyle.
吃雪宝吗
Snoball?
看来这儿不是天堂
Guess this isn't heaven.
我们找到了罪魁祸首
We found out who screwed up.
你
You.
源头就是你那工业强度的抗菌洗手液
It was your industrial-strength antibacterial soap.
其中额外添加的三氯生起了两种有效的作用
The additional triclosan does two things well:
杀灭耐甲氧西林金黄色葡萄球菌
Kills MRSA
还有搞乱你的甲状腺
and makes your thyroid look stupid.
甲状腺误以为三氯是一种真正的荷尔蒙
It thinks the triclosan is a real hormone
然后关闭
and closes up shop.
长期超量使用
Excessive use over time
加上长期过量饮用这个
combined with excessive use of this
导致了甲状腺功能减退
led to hypothyroidism.
直到表现为精神异常才被诊断
Which went undiagnosed until it presented with psychosis.
急诊使用的镇静剂
When the ER put you on the sedatives,
导致你发生粘液性水肿
it kicked you into myxedema crisis.
我还真没想过还有这种可能
Don't know that I ever would've thought of that.
豪斯说生活充满讽刺
House told us to look for irony.
救我的不是豪斯
This wasn't House.
我的储物柜钥匙
My locker key.
我会给你独立团队
I'll give you your own team.
谢谢
Thanks.
到了我该走出阴影的时候
But it's time to step out of the shadow.
是时候了
It's about time.
有消息吗
Any news?
还没有
Not yet.
你来是让我劝你留下吗
You come here so I could talk you out of it?
我来谢你
I came to say thank you.
相处甚欢
It's been fun.
甚欢
Fun?
比"我们走过风风雨雨"
Sounded pithier than...
简练多了
"We've shared a variety of situations."
威尔森有消息告诉我
Let me know about Wilson.
为什么放他走
Why did you let him go?
宪法第十三修正案
Legal loophole. 13th Amendment.
亚伯拉罕·林肯戴帽子确实很有型
Abraham Lincoln may have looked great in that hat,
可他的劳工政策...
but his labor policies...
豪斯
House.